<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>markdown on Sergey Moraru</title>
    <link>https://ysrg.github.io/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in markdown on Sergey Moraru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:42:10 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ysrg.github.io/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Closures</title>
      <link>https://ysrg.github.io/posts/javascript-closures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 05:42:10 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ysrg.github.io/posts/javascript-closures/</guid>
      <description>Closures are all around in our code, we just need to recognize and leverage them. They happen as a result of writing code that relies heavily on lexical scope. A closure is a function that is able to remember and access its surrounding lexical scope even when that function is executing outside its lexical scope. Closures are a neat way of dealing with the following two realities of JavaScript:
 Scope is at the function level, not the block level Much of what you do in practice in JavaScript is asynchronous/event driven so there is a need to remember the scope of authored-time function declarations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding &#39;this&#39; in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://ysrg.github.io/posts/understand-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 05:42:10 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ysrg.github.io/posts/understand-this/</guid>
      <description>Scope in Javascript is a set of rules that determines how and where a variable(identifier) can be looked up.
A brief refresher. To understand scope, you need to be familiar with some basics of how Javascript (or any other programming language, really) works. Unlike other languages out there, Javascript code is compiled right before (like &amp;lt; 1ms) execution, which is crazy fast. The main parts of this process are: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>